prezzybox.com 2019-12-24

# Privacy Policy - Prezzybox.com

Prezzybox.com takes the privacy of its customers seriously and is committed to the following policy.   

## Who we are

We are Prezzybox.com Ltd. (Prezzybox, we,, us, or our) a company registered in England and Wales (Company No. 03946124) with a registered office at Hollybank Farmhouse, No Mans Heath Lane, Austrey, Warwickshire, CV9 3EW. 

We are registered with the Information Commissioner in accordance with the Data Protection Act (the Act, Data Protection Registration no. Z9389651). For the purposes of the Act we are the data controller of your personal data. 

## The information we collect

### Information Provided By You

We collect the following personal information on customers who have created orders with us. 

  * Full name
  * Email address
  * Contact telephone number
  * Delivery address
  * Billing address

This information is required to process payment and deliver your order to you and is provided by you to Prezzybox when you place an order with us online or over the telephone. 

### Information Collected Automatically

We store some information automatically as you browse our site, such as the IP address of the device you are visiting with. This is for the purpose of security and gaining information on the way you use the website for market research etc. 

Full details of the information collected automatically is outlined in our **cookie policy.**

## How we use this information

The information you provide to us is used so that we can offer you, the customer, the best experience possible. 

Prezzybox are committed to being transparent when it comes to data and your privacy, if you require any further clarification on any of the information below then please contact us via the method at the bottom of this page. 

We use data that you provide us for the following reasons: 

**Processing your order** \- We use the information you provide to process your order. For example, we need to supply address details to our suppliers and couriers in order for them to dispatch your purchase. 

**Provide you with order details and account information** \- This section of the website allows you to manage your contact details, view a history of conversations and messages with our customer services team and view your order history. 

**Website Tracking** \- Anonymised information is collected when you use the website to help provide users with more relevant content on site. For registered users we also store this anonymised behaviour data against their profile, things like what categories or products you have visited. For users that don't wish to for this to happen then please see our [cookie policy](https://www.prezzybox.com/about/cookies), for registered users that wish to opt out of profile enrichment please [contact us](https://www.prezzybox.com/Thread/NewThread). 

**Offer a better service** \- For example, we use anonymised order data to offer better products for sale. 

**Marketing** \- Unless you give us consent, we do not use information you provide to us as part of placing an order for marketing purposes. You can opt-in or opt-out to receive marketing communications as outlined below. 

**Email Tracking** \- For users that have opted-in to receive marketing emails, we use something called a tracking pixel to monitor the performance of campaigns and send you the most relevant offers. The tracking pixel tracks when you open an email from us and allows us to see information like what type of device you are using and where you are reading from, so we can better tailor content to our users' needs. For instance, so we don't keep sending marketing emails to users that are unresponsive. When you sign up and opt-in to receive email marketing emails from us, we collect the IP address used to register and the date and time of registration. This is so we have a record of when consent was given to us to contact you with marketing messages, in relation to your rights under GDPR. 

**Advertising Online** \- You may see adverts for Prezzybox.com online after visiting the website. We serve these adverts via a variety of advertising networks and ad exchanges. We use a variety of advertising technologies such as: web beacons, pixels, ad tags, cookies and some custom technology maintained by the advertising network (e.g. Facebook’s Marketing Pixel). The ads that you see may be based on the products you have browsed on the website. Please refer to our [cookie policy](https://www.prezzybox.com/about/cookies) for information on how to stop seeing these ads. 

**Research** \- We use anonymised order data for market research purposes. For example, to report on how many orders we had from a city/town in a given period. 

**Analysis** We use anonymised data about how you use the website in order to to monitor traffic and website performance. We use tools like Google Analytics or HotJar to do this. More information about this is found in our cookie policy. For more information on how you can opt-out of sending information to Google Analytics, see Google's support document [here](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/181881?hl=en-GB). 

**Protecting our website** \- We use data to prevent fraudulent transactions against you, our website, and our other users. 

**Telephone** \- From time to time, we may monitor or record telephone calls for training purposes in order to offer a better service to our customers. 

**Gift Vouchers** \- Gift vouchers are available to purchase on Prezzybox.com. As they are an intangible item, information about the recipient and sender are needed to actually process the voucher order and deliver to the recipient. As part of placing an order for a gift voucher, you give us permission to contact the recipient with the information regarding the voucher on your behalf. 

## Who we share this information with

In order to fulfil our contractual obligation to you as a customer who has placed an order with us, it may be necessary for us to share information with other third party data processors. An example of those third parties can be found below. 

As a customer, you can request to see a comprehensive list of data that we share with other data processors. 

  * **Dispatch/Fulfillment** \- Our warehouse partner and drop-ship suppliers get basic information, like your name and address, so they know where to send your order. 
  * **Couriers** \- Our courier partners will receive address information in order to get your order to you. If you supply it, they may also get your mobile phone number to send you SMS updates regarding your delivery time estimate.
  * **Payment Providers** \- These companies process the actual payment on our behalf when you pay by credit or debit card, they process the payment and they’ll use some information you provide to verify your identity and prevent fraud.
  * **Marketing Software Providers** \- We securely share some data with advertising partners and marketing agencies that help us run our business
  * **Technical Software Providers** \- These companies will get some anonymised data that help them to provide services to us that allow us to host the website and keep it secure. 

As a customer, you can request to see a comprehensive list of data that we share with other data processors. 

We sometimes share anonymised and aggregated information (for example, order data) to report to other third parties on our sales performance over a period of time. 

##  Saved card details and payment information 

Prezzybox do not store card details directly. Instead, any card details you provide are stored securely by our Merchant Bank (AIBMS). Prezzybox store a reference/token to your securely held card details so that the information is retrievable by you - the customer - for repeat purchases. The information is stored in such a way that means we have no access at all to be able to read it. 

### Data Retention

We retain information provided indefinitely as we use it to provide individuals access to information about their order history and to enable communications with our customer service teams etc. 

We also retain customer records in accordance with FCA and PCI policy - as governed by law and in interest of preventing crime and fraud. 

In compliance with GDPR, we respect the individuals right to access, rectification and erasure of personal data. For more information on how to access, edit or erase information we hold please see the relevant points below. 

### Your Rights

In compliance with GDPR and as part of our privacy policy, we inform you as an individual that you have the following rights: 

  * The right to be informed
  * The right of access
  * The right to rectification
  * The right to erasure
  * The right to restrict processing
  * The right to data portability
  * The right to object
  * The right not to be subject to automated decision-making including profiling

### Withdrawing Consent

Marketing communications are only sent to users who explicitly opt-in and give Prezzybox consent, at the time of creating an account, to contact them for marketing purposes (e.g. special offers, discounts, seasonal promotions etc). 

If you are subscribed to our marketing emails and no longer wish to receive them, you can unsubscribe from marketing communications easily by clicking the unsubscribe link located at the bottom of every marketing email. 

Please note that opting out of marketing messages will not stop transactional communications (like updates on your order, delivery information etc). 

Alternatively, please contact a member of our customer services team who will be happy to assist you. 

## Lawful Basis for Processing Personal Data

Prezzybox.com Ltd. have a lawful basis for processing personal data, that you provide at the time of placing an order, in order to fulfil our contractual obligations to you. For example, without using the delivery details that you provide to us at time of purchase, we wouldn't be able to delivery your order to you. 

By placing an order and disclosing this information with us at the time of purchase, you consent to the collection, storage and processing of that information in the manner as set out in this policy. 

This lawful basis for processing personal data is in compliance with the new GDPR as stated in Article 6(1)(b): 

processing is necessary for the performance of a contract to which the data subject is party or in order to take steps at the request of the data subject prior to entering into a contract 

Full information on lawful basis for processing personal data can be found on the [ Information Commissioner's Office website ](https://ico.org.uk/for-organisations/guide-to-the-general-data-protection-regulation-gdpr/lawful-basis-for-processing/contract/)

## Right Of Access: Data Access Requests

In compliance with GDPR, individuals have the right to access your personal data. Individuals have the right to obtain 

  * Confirmation that their data is being processed;
  * Access to your personal data; and
  * Other supplementary information

### What does this mean?

The purpose of right access under GDPR is to clarify the reasons to allow individuals to access their personal data. Individuals should be aware of, and can verify the lawfulness of the processing (details of which can be found above). 

You can request to see a copy of the data that we hold. 

Prezzybox.com have the right to charge a reasonable fee when a request is manifestly unfounded or excessive, particularly if the request is repetitive. Prezzybox.com may also charge a reasonable fee to comply with requests for further copies of the same information. The fee will be based on the administrative costs of providing the information. 

Prezzybox.com must provide this information without delay and within one month of the receipt of the request. This period can be extended by a further two months where requests are numerous or complex. If this is the case then Prezzybox must inform the individual within one month of the receipt of the request and explain why the extension is necessary. 

### What if the request is manifestly unfounded or excessive?

Where requests are manifestly unfounded or excessive, in particular because they are repetitive, Prezzybox.com can: 

  * charge a reasonable fee taking into account the administrative costs of providing the information; or
  * refuse to respond.

Where Prezzybox.com refuse to respond to a request, we must first explain to the individual why we have made this decision and inform them of their right to complain to the supervisory authority and to a judicial remedy without undue delay and at the latest within one month. 

## Snappy Privacy Policy

The protection of your rights and your data is very important to us.

Images uploaded via the Snappy app are transferred via SSL and are always kept secure and confidential. 

Should you go on to place an order, your image will be passed on to one of our partners for the purpose of fulfilling your order.

Your image will be stored securely for up to a year after the date of last access.

We use your images to remove the background via a third-party, and share the edited image with a third-party software partner to apply your image to our personalised product portfolio. 

We also collect anonymised usage data to allow us to analyse use of the platform and continually improve Snappy and the service it provides.

We use cookies in order to provide functionality to the Snappy service. A full explanation of cookies and the types of things they are used for on Prezzybox.com and the Snappy service is available in Prezzybox.com's main privacy policy.

Should you authenticate via Instagram, Snappy will remain authorised to access your Instagram photographs for an hour. 

Authenticating via Facebook will create a Prezzybox.com account for future access.  

## Changes to Privacy Policy

Any changes to this privacy policy will be made on this page. Where possible and appropriate, we will notify you of any significant changes by email. 

## Contact Details

If you require any further assistance with regards to matters of privacy, then please do not   
hesitate to contact our [ customer services team ](https://www.prezzybox.com/Thread/NewThread?threadsubject=General). 

Telephone: 01827 839041 

**Registered Office:**

Prezzybox.com LTD   
Hollybank Farm House   
No Mans Heath Lane   
Austrey   
Warwickshire   
CV9 3EW
